ABDULLAH BILEN

Powercoders Participant

Ibelweg 18c, 6300 Zug | * 01 July 1987 abdullah.bilen@powercoders.org | +41 76 596 66 49

GitHub | Learning Blog | LinkedIn

Languages: English (B2-C1), German (B2), Turkish (C2), Central

Kurdish (C1), Northern Kurdish (mother tongue)

IT skills: Elementary: HTML5, CSS3

Beginner: JavaScript, Git, GitHub

Other IT skills: Advanced: MS Office, Quarkxpress, Corel Draw, Edius

(video editor),

X/Z-Plan, StateX, TabX (media planning and monitoring software, provided

by Ipsos MENA)

Intermediate: Adobe Photoshop

SUMMARY

Self-motivated individual with more than ten years of experience in the media industry. Analytical thinker and creative problem-solver with the ability to communicate effectively with colleagues and learn quickly. Looking for an opportunity to be able to grow my programming skills and to secure an internship in the IT industry.

WORK EXPERIENCE

01/2015 - 03/2018

Head of Media Planning Dept, Edicoo Advertising Agency, Erbil, KRG, Iraq

- Created monthly analysis and reports about the Kurdish and Iraqi media to offer the most effective advertising channels to the clients
- Gained a long-term client with a first mandate of 500k USD
- Prepared a report for Coca Cola company which led them to change their campaign strategy for the country
- Advised the team in preparing the more effective media plans for more than 200 clients

03/2010 - 12/2014

Redactor (remote), ANF (Firat News Agency), Amsterdam, Netherlands

- Founded the Kurdish Service and developed it into a team of 7 people.
- Made ANF Kurdish one of the most clicked news portals among Kurdish news portals.

10/2008 - 05/2010

News Reporter (remote), DİHA (Dicle News Agency), Diyarbakir, Turkey

- Interviewed community members for potential story ideas and feature writing assignments related to the culture and political community.
- Created news stories detailing breaking events.

03/2008 - 09/2008

Editor-Designer, Kowari Hawdam, cultural & political magazine, Erbil, Iraq

- Prepared the first issue of the magazine in a dormitory room.
- Grew the team to more than 10 motivated team members



EDUCATION

09/2020 – 12/2020 Powercoders – Coding Academy for Refugees, Zurich, Switzerland

- Foundations in HTML, CSS, JavaScript; specialization tracks upcoming

- Weekly business & social skills training (teamwork, communication, etc.)

10/2005 – 10/2010 Bachelor Degree in English Language, Salahaddin University-Erbil, Iraq

ADDITIONAL COURSES

07/2016 Media Planning and Audience Measurement (Course), Ipsos, Erbil, Iraq 03/2009 Cameraman, Photographer Courses. Dicle News Agency, Erbil, Iraq

PROMOTION & AWARDS

09/2011 Winner of The Musa Anter Reward for Press Martyrs. 2011, Diyarbakir,

Turkey

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

10/2019 – Present Volunteer Web Designer, FRW Interkultureller Dialog, Baar, Switzerland

Built the website using a content management system, transferred previous

content

12/2019 – Present Teacher, Verein für Kurdischunterricht, Lucerne, Switzerland

- Teaching Kurdish language to children as optional module of the cantonal

schools

CERTIFICATION

08/2018 – 01/2020 German courses, A1-B2.2, ProArbeit, Zug, Switzerland

HOBBIES

- Writing stories for children and modern fables
- Reading novels and stories
- Cooking
- Listening to music and always believes "without music life would be a mistake"

REFERENCES

- Hussam Allaham, Powercoders Industry Lead, hussam.allaham@powercoders.org,
 +41 77 906 16 27
- Veysel Kizilirmak, CEO, Edicoo Advertising Agency, <u>veysel@edicoo.com</u>, +964 750 418 45 35
- Maxime Demiralp, General Director, ANF, <u>azadi.maxime@gmail.com</u>, +32 474 16 75 26